ILGWU Local 10 Minutes 5780/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 10 Minutes
1901-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 10
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/001
17 cubic feet
17 linear ft.
Minutes.
5520630
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D Cohen, August 06, 2003
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
"Permanent deposit".
Local 10 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, was based in New York, New York.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains executive board minutes and calendars, membership meeting minutes, and division minutes of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Local 10, the Amalgamated Ladies Garment Cutters Union. Also contains miscellaneous records of Locals 10, 23, and 25, including files on special meetings, membership committees, and companies.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/001 mf: ILGWU Local 10 Minutes on Microfilm 5780/008: ILGWU Local 10 Dues Books 5780/011: ILGWU Local 10 Managers' Correspondence 5780/012: ILGWU Local 10 Managers' Correspondence 5780/094: ILGWU Local 10 Membership Record Books 5780/131: ILGWU Local 10 Records
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union.; Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union.; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees
5520630
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. I, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. II, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. III, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. IV, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. V, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. VI, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. VII, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. VIII, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. IX, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. X, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XI, 1920-1922 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XII, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XIII, 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XIV, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XV, 1926-1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XVI, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XVII, 1932-1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XVIII, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XIX, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XX, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXI, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXII, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXIII, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXIV, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXV, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXVI, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXVII, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXVIII, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXIX, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXX, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXI, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXII, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXIII [folder 1 of 2], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXIII [folder 2 of 2], 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXIV [folder 1 of 2], 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXIV [folder 2 of 2], 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. Vol. XXXV [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. General. Vol. XXXV [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Calendars, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Calendars, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Calendars, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Executive Board Calendars, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. I, 1906-1909 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. II, 1910-1913 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. III, 1913-1914 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. IV, 1914-1915 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. V, 1916-1924 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. VI, 1925-1933 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. VI, 1933-1940 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. VIII, 1940-1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. IX [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Minutes. Membership. Vol. IX [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Waist and Dress Division Minutes. Membership. Vol. I, 1916-1923 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1916-1917 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1918-1920 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1921-1923 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1923 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1916-1923 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1916-1917 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1920-1922 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cloak and Suit Division., 1922-1923 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Advisory Board Minutes. Waist and Dress Division., 1916 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Divisions Minutes. Membership. Vol. I, 1916-1926 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Divisions Minutes. Membership. Vol. II, 1927-1933 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Executive Board Minutes. Miscellaneous Divisions. Vol. I, 1919-1925 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Executive Board Minutes. Miscellaneous Divisions. Vol. II, 1926-1927 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Divisions Record of Payments., 1918-1920 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Executive Board Minutes. United Cloak and Suit Cutters Association., 1905-1908 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- United Cloak and Suit Cutters Association Minutes. Membership., 1901-1906 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Executive Board Minutes. Cutters Local., 1909-1910 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes. Gotham Knife Cutters Association., 1902-1905 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Gotham Association Minutes. Membership., 1903-1905 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 1, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 2, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 1, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  July through December 1976
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 2, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Local 10 Executive Board, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  January through December 1977
- Local 10 Executive Board, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Local 10 Executive Board, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  January through December 1978
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 1, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 2, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  January through June 1980
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 1, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  June through December 1980
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 2, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  December 1980 through March 1981
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  March through December 1981
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  January through March 1982
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  March through December 1982
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  July 1985 through May 1986
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  May 1986 through May 1987
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  June 1987 through August 1988
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  August 1988 through November 1989
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 1, 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  December 1989 through January 1992
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes Part 2, 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  January 1992 through May 1993
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  May 1993 through May 1994
- Local 10 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1994-1996 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  June 1994 through September 1996
- Amended Rules and Regulations of the Health and Vacation Fund of Local 10, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1946-1953 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1954-1962 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  January through June 1990
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  July through December 1990
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes Pt 1, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  January through September 1991
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes Pt 2, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  September through November 1991
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  November 1991 through March 1992
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  April through July 1992
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  September through November 1992
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  November through December 1992
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  December 1992 through March 1993
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  March through May 1993
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  July through August 1993
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  December 1993 through February 1994
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  April through September 1994
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  November 1994 through March 1995
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  May through December 1995
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes Pt 1, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  February through June 1996
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes Pt 2, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Committee Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  September through December 1996
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  January through February 1997
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  March through April 1997
- Local 10 Health and Vacation Fund Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  May through July 1997
- Local 10 Special Meetings, 1977-1981 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Local 10 Membership Meetings, 1978-1984 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Local 10 Membership Committee Folder 1, 1977-1981 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Local 10 Membership Committee Meetings Folder 2, 1981-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 1, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 2, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 3, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 4, 1973-1976 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 5, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Local 10 Calendars Folder 6, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Leslie Fay Marketing, Inc. Local 10 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Mikan Group Inc.- Local 10, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Garden State Cutting, 1996-2004 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Mayflower Fashions Local 23-35, 10, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Mayflower Fashions Local 23-35, 10, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 20)